# Johandry Amador

Phone: (858) 281-3450, San Diego, CA 92127

Email: johandry@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/johandry/

Web: http://www.johandry.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Infrastructure, DevOps and Software Engineer with 15+ years of experience working for 500 Fortune companies. Certified Kubernetes Application Developer and Docker Certified Associate. Sysadmin with 15+ years of experience automating every process using Bash, Ruby, Perl and Python. Go passionate developer with +3 years of experience making CLI, web UI and microservices with REST and gRPC APIs. Cloud Engineer working with AWS and other clouds and platforms, automating tasks with CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible and Puppet.

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Go Developer
- Bash, Perl, Python
- Angular & React
- TLS

- Kubernetes
- Docker
- Microservices
- gRPC

- AWS & GCP
- Unix Administrator
- Terraform
- Ansible & Puppet

Other Skills: Ruby, NodeJS, YAML, JSON, Vagrant, Packer, Jenkins, Travis, CircleCI, Git, Swarm, vmWare, OpenStack, Helm, Azure, F5, Presto, SQLite, MongoDB, Apache Web Server, JBoss, Nginx, Scrum, Kanban, Technical and Project Manager (1:12), Jira.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Cloud Engineer & Go Developer - Teradata, San Diego, CA

Nov 2016 - Present

- Development of KubeKit, an application used by all Teradata to install and configure Kubernetes clusters to install on top of it all the Teradata applications to the clients. https://github.com/liferaft/kubekit
- Development of a Terraformer (aka Terranova) and integration with KubeKit, a Go package that uses Terraform Go code to allow KubeKit to provision multiple Kubernetes nodes and resources on AWS, EKS, AKS, vSphere, OpenStack and Baremetal through Stacki using Terraform templates. https://github.com/johandry/terranova
- o Development of different Go packages to facilitate communication with Ansible processes, generate mTLS certificates, Kubernetes API client, gRPC & REST API server and client in Go and Python.
- o Migration from a CLI monolithic made in Go to microservices using gRPC and REST API.
- Development of Reeve, a decentralized event-driven configuration manager based on Serf and made in Go.
- Use of Docker, Docker Compose and local Kubernetes as development environment for developed microservices and Reeve.
- o Use of Jenkins, Travis and GitHub Actions for the CI & CD of the developed applications.
- o Creation of AWS Images (AMI) with Packer and Ansible
- o Use of Molecule and Goss on Docker to test the developed Ansible roles
- o Provisioning of AWS resources (EC2, PVC, SG, ASG, EKS, ECS, S3, Route 53) using CloudFormation and Terraform
- o Development of a CloudFormation and publish on AWS Market Place to create a Presto cluster.
- o Containerization of Presto to make a Presto cluster on Kubernetes.
- Documentation with Markdown

# **Kubernetes Administrator & Developer** – Freelance Software Developer, San Diego, CA Jan 2018 – Aug 2018

- o Migration of a monolithic application to microservices to run on Kubernetes on AWS.
- Setup of Kubernetes services on AWS with Route53 and Let's Encrypt TLS certificates.
- Setup of ECS to store the developed microservices in Docker containers.
- Use of Docker Compose as local development environment
- Development of multiple Docker containers, each one running React, PHP, Go, OpenCVS, Caffe and TensorFlow applications. Deployment of such containers to Kubernetes Pods.
- Setup of Kubernetes nodes with CoreOS for GPU Nvidia using cloud-config.
- Setup of ELK (Elasticsearch, Fluentd & Kibana) on Kubernetes

- Deployment of ConfigMaps, Secrets and Volumes on Kubernetes
- Documentation with Markdown

# DevOps Engineer - FICO, San Diego, CA

Jul 2015 - Nov 2016

- Development of Puppet modules with Hiera, r10k and Jenkins for automation, CI/CD of managed products and related services.
- Use of Bitbucket and Git for control version and repository management
- o Use of Foreman, Foreman API and Vagrant to lifecycle management of virtual servers in Non-Production environments on VirtualBox and vSphere.
- Management of virtual servers and storage on vSphere.
- o Development of VM images with Packer to be used with Vagrant on VirtualBox and vSphere.
- o Ownership and support of 7 Products with 3 layers in Non-Production environments.
- Design of Infrastructure Diagrams, creation of Bills of Materials (BoM) and validation of Software Architecture Document (SAD).
- o Administration of JBoss and Glassfish, manually and with Puppet.
- Use of F5 to configure load balance and high availability.
- o Creation and management of VIP with NPM and F5. DNS management with Infoblox.
- Single Sign On configuration with OKTA using the OKTA Console. Manual configuration and using Puppet at the application side.
- Zabbix and Keynote configuration for monitoring of servers and services on every environment (Production and Non-Production).
- o Configuration of TLS with mutual authentication, manually and with Puppet.
- o Management of MySQL, Couchbase, Elasticsearch, Apache Web Server, Apache MQ, Apache Tomcat using Puppet and manually.
- o Installation and configuration of Vormetric on Unix systems.
- o Installation and upgrade of Tableau Server.
- Use of ServiceNow and Kanban for incident management, change control and task management.
- Documentation of processes with Markdown.

#### System Administrator & Unix Developer - Global HITSS, Aguascalientes, Mexico

Worldwide Attended Business: Amdocs, AT&T and Yellow Pages

Sep 2013 - Jul 2015

- o Automation of Unix Admin tasks developing Bash scripts and Perl application.
- Development and maintenance of Kairos, a job scheduler and event driven file transfer similar to AutoSys or Jenkins, used by Yellow Pages to transfer remote files and execute remote commands. <a href="https://github.com/johandry/kairos">https://github.com/johandry/kairos</a>
- Development of Kairos CLI and backend using Perl and Dancer Web framework, MySQL and MongoDB.
- o Development of Kairos Web interface using AngularJS, ¡Query, and Bootstrap.
- o Provisioning, Configuration Management and shipping of development and testing environments using Docker, Fig (former Docker Compose), Packer, Vagrant and Puppet on VirtualBox and AWS.
- Deployment of Kairos to multiple servers in testing and production environments using Jenkins, Git and Docker.
- Configuration Management of 200+ servers with Puppet, Git, Hiera and Hiera-eyaml.
- Development and maintenance of a Sysadmin web dashboard to centralize tools and reports of System Patches, NetApp differences, Nagios monitoring dashboard, Servers Inventory using Facter and others, the application is continuously growing. The CLI and backend was developed using Perl, Dancer2 using Moo (Perl Object Oriented), Bash and MongoDB. Use of JSON files to transfer data to the frontend, which was developed with AngularJS, jQuery and Bootstrap.
- Development of the Sysadmin web dashboard improved version using MEAN (instead of LAMP) with NodeJS, Express and MongoDB.
- Migration of 100+ servers and applications from a datacenter to the IBM cloud (SoftLayer) using Puppet and Git.
- Manual execution of Sysadmin activities such as Storage Management with NetApp, Server Virtualization Management with vmWare and other general Sysadmin tier/level 1 tasks on Windows, RedHat ES, Ubuntu, CentOS and HPUX, virtual and baremetal.
- o On-Call service non-business hours every 6 weeks.

# Previous work experience

At Softtek Information Services, Aguascalientes, Mex

- o **Technical Leader and Senior Sysadmin** Electronic Arts and Burger King, Nov 2012 Sep 2013
- o **Program Manager and QA & UAT Program Manager** Walmart, May 2008 Nov 2012
- Technical Leader, Infrastructure Architect and Senior Sysadmin General Electric, Aug 2003 May 2008

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Computer Science, Universidad de la Habana, Havana, Cuba.

2000

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD), The Linux Foundation – CKAD-1900-002103-0100	Dec 2019
Certified Puppet Professional, Puppet – PCP204-0090	Oct 2016
Certified Docker Associate, <i>Docker</i> – 11632820	Jun 2018

## **COURSES**

Kubernetes Fundamentals for Certified Kubernetes Administration (CKA)

2019